Klain, James M. School of Theater, Film & Television photographs. 1931-1997; n.d. UARC.0671
UCLA Library Special Collections
Klain, James M. School of Theater, Film & Television photographs.
1931-1997; n.d.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Klain, James M.
UARC.0671
0.4 Linear Feet (1 box)
Record Series 671 contains photographs taken and/or collected by James M. Klain on behalf of UCLA's School of Theater, Film, and Television.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9944751043606533
Biographical note
James M. Klain earned his Bachelor of Arts in Drama at UCLA in 1943, and although he did not obtain further degrees, continued his studies there in Theater Arts and Education. Klain went on to work at UCLA as the director of the Campus Activities Service Office, directed the renovation of Royce Hall (1982-1984), served as stage manager at such venues as the Royce Hall Auditorium and Pauley Pavilion (1947-), and held positions as charter member and Vice President of the Theater, Film and Television Alumni Association.
Scope and Content
Record Series 671 contains photographs taken and/or collected by James M. Klain on behalf of UCLA's School of Theater, Film, and Television. These black and white and color photographs document such subjects as events held by the School of Theater, Film, and Television; the renovation of Royce Hall in the early 1980's; sculptures and signage around campus; and other campus events. Additionally, files include some promotional materials for UCLA and the School of Theater, Film, and Television.
This is an inactive record series; no additional University records are expected to be added.
- Moore Hall., 1931. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Graduates., c.1940s. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Backstage at Royce Hall., c.1948-1950. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Jackie Robinson sculpture and plaque., 1981; 1985. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Royce Hall - aftermath of earthquake., 1994. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1949 Summer Workshop film photos., 1997. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- School of Theater, Film, and Television 50th Anniversary banner., 1997. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Macgowen Hall, Melnitz Hall, and Freud Playhouse plaques., c.1997. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- UCLA Motion Picture Soundstage. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Slides of campus photos., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Assorted photos. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes black and white photo of roofing project at UCLA (n.d.), color photos taken at the Steinway Piano Factory in New York (1977), a color photo of United States President Johnson and Mexican President Adolfo Lopez-Mateos landing on campus in a helicopter (taken by Thelner Hoover, 1964), and a color photo and accompanying slide of a wall applique at Schoenberg Hall (n.d.).
- S. David Saxon Archive photos., 1951-1957. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Includes photos of various stage productions.
- John Young Archive photos., c.1951. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes photos of various film and stage productions.
- UCLA promotional material., 1937-1984. (Box 1, Folder 14)